

# **Alex Papadopoulos**

# **UX Researcher & Designer**

London, UK

me@imalexnow.io

+44 747 8324 540

imalexnow.io

# WHAT I DO

I am a Researcher with a background in Psychology and Human-Computer Interaction

# **ABOUT ME**

Have great aptitude of conducting qualitative and quantitative research.

As a User Experience professional, my first priority is to put users at the center of any product or service and care for their needs. Can confidently present research to key stakeholders and make justified recommendations.

# **SKILLS**

Key Skills

User Research, Research Design, Qualtitative and Quantitative Research Statistical Analysis, Contextual Design, Ethnographic Research, Interviews Personas Development, User Requirements Elicitation, Heuristic Reviews Prototyping, Wireframing, Storyboarding, Use Case Scenarios

IT Skills

Adobe XD, Sketch, InVision, Balsamiq Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, R SPSS Statistics

## **EXPERIENCE**

Dec 2016 - Aug 2019

#### PhD Researcher

University College London

- Planned and designed Usability, Accessibility, and User Research sessions to support the design and development of digital services on projects which were run at the ExCiteS research group funded by the European Commission:
- Projects worked on: WeGovNow https://www.wegovnow.eu/, DiToS http://www.togetherscience.eu/, Ecsanvis https://www.geog.ucl.ac.uk/research/research-centres/excites/projects/extremecitizen-science-analysis-and-visualisation-ecsanvis
- Recruited users for testing sessions and carrying out research
- Used research results to communicate ideas and decide product or service needs and design direction
- Anticipated interaction problems
- Helped colleagues understand user behaviours
- Presented user insights to project stakeholders at all levels

May 2019 - July 2019

#### Research Assistant

Centre of Longitudinal Studies (CLS)

Identified new tools and areas of research for nationwide long term research e.g.
 technical solutions to measure screen time and online behaviour in adults. The

importance of identifying these tools was to reduce the time spent creating reports, improve reporting accuracy which is not always accurate, as well as increase the amount of data collected in order to have a holistic view of what a user

Presented report and reasoning of using these new tools to key stakeholders at a
workshop and they were discussed for feasibility and costs for implementation. The
CLS approved of the tools and are planning to carry research with them within the next
year

Jan 2017 - June 2019

#### **Teaching Assistant**

University College London

i. Introduction to Citizen Science and Scientific Crowdsourcing (2018-2019)

ii. GIS Design (2017)

May 2016 - July 2016

#### **User Research Assistant**

Sony Computer Entertainment Europe

- Assisted in carrying out user testing of a Virtual Reality game for PlayStation 4
- Processed NDA agreements from participants of the user testing. Explained to them
  the process of the game. Helped them with putting on their VR headsets, assisted
  them when they needed clarifications on the aspects of the game.
- Helped participants fill their questionnaires at allocated times, and answered their questions at the end of the user testing as well as mediated a small discussion about the game they have tested

## **EDUCATION**

Dec 2016 - Dec 2019

University College London, London

PhD, Human-Computer Interaction

Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

University College London, London

Master of Science, Human-Computer Interaction with Ergonomics (Merit)

Sep 2012 - Jun 2015

University of Sheffield International Faculty, City College, Thessaloniki

Bachelor of Science, Psychology (2.1)

## **SEMINARS**

Sep 2019

Copywriting for the Web

General Assembly

Oct 2019

Service Design

General Assembly

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

**UX** Techdegree

Team Treehouse

# **PUBLICATIONS**

2017

#### International Journal of Game-Based learning

Jennett, C., Papadopoulou, S., Himmelstein, J., Vaugoux, A., Roger, V., & Cox, A. L. Students' Experiences of Interdisciplinary Learning while Building Scientific Video Games.

2018

#### Collective Intelligence 2018

Repetition Doesn't Have To Be Boring: User Experience Design For Online Citizen Science Data Classification Applications

## **INTERESTS**

Writing childrens' stories, Stage Lighting Design and Operation, Reading whatever falls into my hands